<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Petr Kubelka</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Petr Kubelka</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 21:05:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes: Doors Of Perception</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/books/doors_of_perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 21:05:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/books/doors_of_perception/</guid>
      
      <description>This was a very difficult audiobook to listen to because it was full of long sentences. (Here, remove &amp;ldquo;as it was&amp;rdquo; for a smoother flow)
For example:
Modern Sentence: The house was big. 1950s Sentence: The sprawling Victorian mansion loomed over the quaint street, its imposing façade casting a long shadow in the afternoon sun. Even though it was only a two-hour listen, I almost gave up on it.
Huxley describes the profound impact mescaline had on his senses, particularly vision.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes: The Art of War</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/books/the_art_of_war/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 19:02:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/books/the_art_of_war/</guid>
      
      <description>Spies and deception used everywhere through the book. Deception and Misdirection: Military strategy relies heavily on creating illusions and manipulating your opponent&amp;rsquo;s perception. This translates to using tactics like feints, appearing weak when strong, and strong when weak, to gain the upper hand. &amp;ldquo;All warfare is based on deception.&amp;rdquo; Adaptability and Opportunity: Warfare is ever-changing, and so should your approach. The ability to adapt to new situations and seize opportunities that arise from chaos is a key theme.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes: Entangled Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/books/entangled_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 17:16:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/books/entangled_life/</guid>
      
      <description>Entangled Life by Merlin Sheldrake delves into the fascinating world of fungi, revealing surprising and sometimes bizarre facts about these complex organisms. Here are some of the most interesting stuff:
The Wood Wide Web: Fungi form vast underground networks of interconnected threads called mycelium, which function like an internet for the forest. These networks allow trees and other plants to communicate and share resources.
Zombie Ants: A specific fungus can hijack the brains of ants, turning them into mindless puppets.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/042024/042024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 21:00:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/042024/042024/</guid>
      
      <description>Random Topics Intro Quick month, much injury (twisted ankle during bouldering, twisted finger during krav maga) Engineering leadership Visited ELCZ + ProductTank Praha: Build synergies over processes and metrics between PM and EM Much appreciated networking in old Avast offices :3 Psyres LSD day Visited Psyres and Czeched substance at Cross Club where they presented state of psychedelics ad harm reduction in Czech Republic.
Runescape 20 years Book I enjoy very much where there are anecdotes and lore shared about RuneScape development:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: How to Plan an MVP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/yc_mba/week2/how_to_plan_an_mvp/how_to_plan_an_mvp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 15:54:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/yc_mba/week2/how_to_plan_an_mvp/how_to_plan_an_mvp/</guid>
      
      <description>MVP (Minimal Viable Product): It&amp;rsquo;s crucial to start with something ridiculously simple to give to the first users, checking if we can add any value to them. Some understanding of the problem is very helpful when building an MVP, so please talk to your users before writing code. There&amp;rsquo;s no need for three years of research, but some is fine. Even better if you are the user. How to get first users is a weird question because the reason to start a startup is to solve somebody else&amp;rsquo;s or your own problem.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/032024/032024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 18:53:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/032024/032024/</guid>
      
      <description>Random Topics Intro I feel like I didn&amp;rsquo;t accomplish much this month. This monthly blog helped me realize I managed to do at least something. Austria Skiing We visited Restaurant Week for the second time. This time we selected Hong Kong Karlin. The food itself was okay, but the staff was slow, and the food came colder than expected. We were also hungry after the whole fine dining thing, so we needed to go to McDonald&amp;rsquo;s to eat something more.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book notes: The Mom Test</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/books/moms_test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 11:18:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/books/moms_test/</guid>
      
      <description>The Mom Test Talk about their life instead of your idea Ask about specifics in the past instead of generics or opinions about the future Talk less and listen more It’s called The Mom Test because it leads to questions that even your mom can’t lie to you about. When you do it right, they won’t even know you have an idea. There are some other important tools and tricks that we’ll introduce throughout the rest of the book.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: How to talk to users</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/yc_mba/week1/how_to_talk_to_users/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 23:05:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/yc_mba/week1/how_to_talk_to_users/</guid>
      
      <description>startup ideas just does not happen on Lazy sunday morning How to talk to users 01 Why the best founders talk to their users throughout the lifetime of the company Talk to customer even before you have product Users Who should you talk to people in your network coworkers people you don&amp;rsquo;t know linkedin reddit &amp;hellip; in person events (meetups, make a meetup!) process Starting a new startup My plan 01 Interview potential customers 02 Learn about the problems &amp;amp; motivations around carbon emissions 03 Understand what an MVP will look like (minimum viable product) Speak with founders, CEO&amp;rsquo;s, CFO&amp;rsquo;s at different sized companies people that work in companies with titles that include carbon, climate, .</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes: How to get and Test Startup Ideas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/yc_mba/week0/get_and_test_startup_ideas/get_and_test_startup_ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 23:07:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/yc_mba/week0/get_and_test_startup_ideas/get_and_test_startup_ideas/</guid>
      
      <description>start with the problem do i have any relation with problem do i have the problem, family, friends? personal connection might help Brainstorm with friends once found interesting prolblem Why Are You Uniquely Qualified to Work on This Problem? not meant in usual CV way (25 years of experience) some angle i understand others doesnt? some way of attacking the problem i have and others do not. What’s the unique insight?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YCombinator Startup school MBA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/yc_mba/yc_mba/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 23:02:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/yc_mba/yc_mba/</guid>
      
      <description>Motivation I was offered to study MBA program by my job at university. When searching what usually MBA programs consist of I found Ycombinator startup school and somebody on hackernews posted list of videos that makes good MBA program. I quite like it so I decided to go through these vids and makes notes out of it:
WEEK 0: My own - How to get and Test Startup ideas Notes: How to get and Test Startup idea</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/022024/022024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 20:14:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/022024/022024/</guid>
      
      <description>Random topics Mallorca 4 days of hiking next to the beach, through mountains. Sun and cactuses everywhere.
Superbowl I was able to obtain commented session of superbowl. Superbowl was full of ads and weirds bets on Taylor Swift, streakers and similiar stuff.
The Guardian - Super Bowl: illegal bets surge as gambling experts warn of black market risks Business Insider - The Super Bowl streaker bet on himself, but this time it was a prop bet New York Post - Suspicious betting raises questions about Super Bowl Gatorade color odds News.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      
      <description>This is my attempt to revive my blog and try to summarize stuff that is happening in my life at least once a month.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misc</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pages/misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 21:42:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pages/misc/</guid>
      
      <description>Miscellaneous treasures This section has random links for all kind of interesting stuff. Articles, Videos, Podcast and Newsletters.
Articles These are articles I consider somehow outstanding.
Several Articles from Michael Lynch how to make code review properly. Human code reviews 1 Human code reviews 2 How to Make Your Code Reviewer Fall in Love with You Floating point error killing people Bruteforcing Instagram 2FA and gaining access JL Collins and his Simple Path to Wealth Various sorces from The Cursed Computer Iceberg Meme, I highly recommend you to read it all!</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pages/about/</guid>
      
      <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
